import GLA1 from "./GLA1.mp4"
import GLA2 from "./GLA2.mp4"
import GLA3 from "./GLA3.mp4"
import GLA4 from "./GLA4.mp4"
import GLA5 from "./GLA5.mp4"
import GLA6 from "./GLA6.mp4"
import GLA7 from "./GLA7.mp4"
import GLA8 from "./GLA8.mp4"
import GLA9 from "./GLA9.mp4"
import GLA10 from "./GLA10.mp4"
import GLA11 from "./GLA11.mp4"
import GLA12 from "./GLA12.mp4"
import GLA13 from "./GLA13.mp4"
import GLA14 from "./GLA14.mp4"
import GLA15 from "./GLA15.mp4"
import GLA16 from "./GLA16.mp4"
import GLA17 from "./GLA17.mp4"
import GLA18 from "./GLA18.mp4"
import GLA19 from "./GLA19.mp4"
import GLA20 from "./GLA20.mp4"
import GLA21 from "./GLA21.mp4"
import GLA22 from "./GLA22.mp4"
import GLA23 from "./GLA23.mp4"
import GLA24 from "./GLA24.mp4"
import GLA25 from "./GLA25.mp4"
import GLA26 from "./GLA26.mp4"
import GLA27 from "./GLA27.mp4"
import GLA28 from "./GLA28.mp4"
import GLA29 from "./GLA29.mp4"
import GLA30 from "./GLA30.mp4"
import GLA31 from "./GLA31.mp4"
import GLA32 from "./GLA32.mp4"
import GLA33 from "./GLA33.mp4"
import GLA34 from "./GLA34.mp4"
import GLA35 from "./GLA35.mp4"
import GLA36 from "./GLA36.mp4"
import GLA37 from "./GLA37.mp4"
import GLA38 from "./GLA38.mp4"
import GLA39 from "./GLA39.mp4"
import GLA40 from "./GLA40.mp4"
import GLA41 from "./GLA41.mp4"
import GLA43 from "./GLA43.mp4"
import GLA44 from "./GLA44.mp4"
import GLA45 from "./GLA45.mp4"
import GLA46 from "./GLA46.mp4"
import GLA47 from "./GLA47.mp4"
import GLA48 from "./GLA48.mp4"
import GLA49 from "./GLA49.mp4"
import GLA50 from "./GLA50.mp4"
import GLA51 from "./GLA51.mp4"
import GLA52 from "./GLA52.mp4"
import GLA53 from "./GLA53.mp4"
import GLA54 from "./GLA54.mp4"
import GLA55 from "./GLA55.mp4"
import GLA56 from "./GLA56.mp4"
import GLA57 from "./GLA57.mp4"
import GLA58 from "./GLA58.mp4"
import GLA59 from "./GLA59.mp4"
import GLA60 from "./GLA60.mp4"
import GLA62 from "./GLA62.mp4"
import GLA63 from "./GLA63.mp4"
import GLA64 from "./GLA64.mp4"
import GLA65 from "./GLA65.mp4"
import GLA66 from "./GLA66.mp4"
import GLA67 from "./GLA67.mp4"
import GLA68 from "./GLA68.mp4"
import GLA69 from "./GLA69.mp4"
import GLA70 from "./GLA70.mp4"
import GLA71 from "./GLA71.mp4"
import GLA72 from "./GLA72.mp4"
import GLA73 from "./GLA73.mp4"
import GLA74 from "./GLA74.mp4"
import GLA75 from "./GLA75.mp4"
import GLA76 from "./GLA76.mp4"
import GLA77 from "./GLA77.mp4"
import GLA78 from "./GLA78.mp4"
import GLA79 from "./GLA79.mp4"
import GLA80 from "./GLA80.mp4"
import GLA81 from "./GLA81.mp4"
import GLA82 from "./GLA82.mp4"
import GLA83 from "./GLA83.mp4"
import GLA84 from "./GLA84.mp4"
import GLA85 from "./GLA85.mp4"
import GLA86 from "./GLA86.mp4"
import GLA87 from "./GLA87.mp4"
import GLA88 from "./GLA88.mp4"
import GLA89 from "./GLA89.mp4"
import GLA90 from "./GLA90.mp4"
import GLA91 from "./GLA91.mp4"
import GLA92 from "./GLA92.mp4"
import GLA93 from "./GLA93.mp4"
import GLA94 from "./GLA94.mp4"
import GLA95 from "./GLA95.mp4"
import GLA96 from "./GLA96.mp4"
import GLA97 from "./GLA97.mp4"
import GLA98 from "./GLA98.mp4"
import GLA99 from "./GLA99.mp4"
import GLA100 from "./GLA100.mp4"
import GLA101 from "./GLA101.mp4"
import GLA102 from "./GLA102.mp4"
import GLA103 from "./GLA103.mp4"
import GLA105 from "./GLA105.mp4"
import GLA106 from "./GLA106.mp4"
import GLA107 from "./GLA107.mp4"
import GLA108 from "./GLA108.mp4"
import GLA109 from "./GLA109.mp4"
import GLA110 from "./GLA110.mp4"


export const GladData = [
    {
        id: 584,
        videoFile: GLA110,
        rusQuestion: "восстановлен в должности",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to give someone back their previous job or position, or to cause something to exist again:",
        answer: "reinstate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
        
    },
    {
        id: 583,
        videoFile: GLA109,
        rusQuestion: "вложи свой меч в ножны",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to put a knife back inside its sheath",
        answer: "sheathe",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 582,
        videoFile: GLA108,
        rusQuestion: "скрывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to prevent something from being seen or known about:",
        answer: "conceal",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 581,
        videoFile: GLA107,
        rusQuestion: "пристегнуть , ремень",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a narrow piece of leather or other strong material used for fastening something or giving support:",
        answer: "strap",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 580,
        videoFile: GLA106,
        rusQuestion: "поразительная история",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "very unusual or easily noticed, and therefore attracting a lot of attention:",
        answer: "striking story",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 579,
        videoFile: GLA105,
        rusQuestion: "потомство",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the young or offspring of a person, animal, or plant:",
        answer: "progeny",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 578,
        videoFile: GLA103,
        rusQuestion: "спаситель",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who saves someone from danger or harm",
        answer: "savior",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 577,
        videoFile: GLA102,
        rusQuestion: "убедительный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "making you want to do or believe a particular thing:",
        answer: "persuasive",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 576,
        videoFile: GLA101,
        rusQuestion: "истекать кровью",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "past simple and past participle of bleed",
        answer: "bled",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 575,
        videoFile: GLA100,
        rusQuestion: "гнилой",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "decayed and having an unpleasant smell:",
        answer: "putrid",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 574,
        videoFile: GLA99,
        rusQuestion: "переворот",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sudden illegal, often violent, taking of government power, especially by part of an army:",
        answer: "coup",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 573,
        videoFile: GLA98,
        rusQuestion: "полумеры",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "actions that only achieve part of what they are intended to achieve:",
        answer: "half measures",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 572,
        videoFile: GLA97,
        rusQuestion: "тайно проносить , переправлять",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to take things or people to or from a place secretly and often illegally:",
        answer: "smuggle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 571,
        videoFile: GLA96,
        rusQuestion: "разжиревший",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to give an animal or a thin person a lot of food so that they become fatter:",
        answer: "fattened",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 570,
        videoFile: GLA95,
        rusQuestion: "грызть , покусывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to eat something by taking a lot of small bites:",
        answer: "nibble",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 569,
        videoFile: GLA94,
        rusQuestion: "мученик",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who suffers very much or is killed because of their religious or political beliefs, and is often admired because of it:",
        answer: "martyr",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 568,
        videoFile: GLA93,
        rusQuestion: "бросая вызов",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to refuse to obey a person, decision, law, situation, etc.:",
        answer: "defy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 567,
        videoFile: GLA92,
        rusQuestion: "пятки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the rounded back part of the foot",
        answer: "heels",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 566,
        videoFile: GLA91,
        rusQuestion: "опустошать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cause great damage to something or someone:",
        answer: "ravage",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 565,
        videoFile: GLA90,
        rusQuestion: "стонал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make a long, low sound of pain, suffering, or another strong emotion:",
        answer: "moan",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 564,
        videoFile: GLA89,
        rusQuestion: "визжал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make a long, very high sound or cry:",
        answer: "squeal",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 563,
        videoFile: GLA88,
        rusQuestion: "милосердный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who is oooo is willing to be kind to and forgive people who are in their power:",
        answer: "merciful",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 562,
        videoFile: GLA87,
        rusQuestion: "устроенный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to plan, prepare for, or organize something:",
        answer: "arrange",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 561,
        videoFile: GLA86,
        rusQuestion: "непостоянный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "likely to change your opinion or your feelings suddenly and without a good reason:",
        answer: "fickle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 560,
        videoFile: GLA85,
        rusQuestion: "на пенсии",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the act of leaving your job and stopping working, usually because you are old:",
        answer: "retirement",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 559,
        videoFile: GLA84,
        rusQuestion: "он соизволил",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "condescend to do something usually humorous",
        answer: "deign",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 558,
        videoFile: GLA83,
        rusQuestion: "вульгарный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "not suitable, simple, dignified or beautiful; not in the style preferred by the upper classes of society:",
        answer: "vulgar",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 557,
        videoFile: GLA82,
        rusQuestion: "выступать против",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to disagree with something or someone, often by speaking or fighting against it, him, or her:",
        answer: "oppose",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 556,
        videoFile: GLA81,
        rusQuestion: "наследник",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who will legally receive money, property, or a title from another person, especially an older member of the same family, when that other person dies:",
        answer: "heir",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 555,
        videoFile: GLA80,
        rusQuestion: "я плакала по ним",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cry tears:",
        answer: "weep",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 554,
        videoFile: GLA79,
        rusQuestion: "распятый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to kill someone by tying or fastening them with nails to a cross and leaving them there to die",
        answer: "crucified",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 553,
        videoFile: GLA78,
        rusQuestion: "убийцы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who kills a famous or important person, usually for political reasons or in exchange for money:",
        answer: "assassin",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 552,
        videoFile: GLA76,
        rusQuestion: "предательство",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "behaviour that deceives or is not loyal to someone who trusts you:",
        answer: "treachery",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 551,
        videoFile: GLA75,
        rusQuestion: "меня это раздражает",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cause difficulty to someone, or to cause someone to feel angry, annoyed, or upset:",
        answer: "vex",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 550,
        videoFile: GLA74,
        rusQuestion: "скорее , охотнее , пожалуй",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "in preference to, or as a preference:",
        answer: "rather",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 549,
        videoFile: GLA73,
        rusQuestion: "туманный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "ooo air or weather is not clear, especially because of heat:",
        answer: "hazy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 548,
        videoFile: GLA72,
        rusQuestion: "колесницы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a two-wheeled vehicle that was used in ancient times for racing and fighting and was pulled by a horse or horses",
        answer: "chariot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 547,
        videoFile: GLA71,
        rusQuestion: "орда , банда",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large group of people:",
        answer: "horde",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 546,
        videoFile: GLA70,
        rusQuestion: "наемники",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a soldier who fights for any country or group that pays them",
        answer: "mercenary",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 545,
        videoFile: GLA70,
        rusQuestion: "свирепый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "frightening and violent:",
        answer: "ferocious",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 544,
        videoFile: GLA69,
        rusQuestion: "равнина",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large area of flat land at low elevation (= height above the surface of the earth):",
        answer: "plain",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 543,
        videoFile: GLA69,
        rusQuestion: "пустошь , неплодородный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "unable to produce plants or fruit:",
        answer: "barren",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 542,
        videoFile: GLA68,
        rusQuestion: "античность",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the distant past (= a long time ago), especially before the sixth century:",
        answer: "antiquity",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 541,
        videoFile: GLA68,
        rusQuestion: "освященный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "holy: very respected and praised because of great importance or great age:",
        answer: "hallowed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 540,
        videoFile: GLA67,
        rusQuestion: "нищий",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a poor person who lives by asking others for money or food",
        answer: "beggar",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 539,
        videoFile: GLA66,
        rusQuestion: "резня",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an act of killing a lot of people:",
        answer: "massacre",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 538,
        videoFile: GLA65,
        rusQuestion: "роспуск",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the ending of esp. an official organization or a legal arrangement:",
        answer: "dissolution",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 537,
        videoFile: GLA64,
        rusQuestion: "удача , состояние",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large amount of money, goods, property, etc.:",
        answer: "fortune",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 536,
        videoFile: GLA63,
        rusQuestion: "кормить грудью",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to feed a baby, especially a baby animal, with milk from the organ in the mother that produces milk, or (of a baby, especially a baby animal) to drink milk from the mother:",
        answer: "suckle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 535,
        videoFile: GLA62,
        rusQuestion: "зараженный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of animals and insects that carry disease) to cause a problem by being present in large numbers:",
        answer: "infest",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 534,
        videoFile: GLA60,
        rusQuestion: "мрамор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of very hard rock that has a pattern of lines going through it, feels cold, and can be polished to become smooth and shiny:",
        answer: "marble",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 533,
        videoFile: GLA59,
        rusQuestion: "вызывать в воображении",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make something appear by magic, or as if by magic:",
        answer: "conjure",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 532,
        videoFile: GLA58,
        rusQuestion: "совращенный , соблазнил",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to persuade or trick someone into doing something by making it very attractive:",
        answer: "seduce",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 531,
        videoFile: GLA57,
        rusQuestion: "скучный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: " C1 boring:",
        answer: "tedious",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 530,
        videoFile: GLA56,
        rusQuestion: "красивое зрелище",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an idea or mental image of something:",
        answer: "vision",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 529,
        videoFile: GLA55,
        rusQuestion: "варвар",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a member of a group of people from a very different country or culture that is considered to be less socially advanced and more violent than your own:",
        answer: "barbarian",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 528,
        videoFile: GLA54,
        rusQuestion: "применения",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a purpose for which something is used:",
        answer: "uses",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 527,
        videoFile: GLA53,
        rusQuestion: "читать мне лекции",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to talk angrily or seriously to someone in order to criticize their behaviour:",
        answer: "to lecture me",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 526,
        videoFile: GLA52,
        rusQuestion: "послушание , повиновение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the fact that people or animals do what they are told to do:",
        answer: "obedience",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 525,
        videoFile: GLA51,
        rusQuestion: "обширный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "covering a large area; having a great range:",
        answer: "extensive",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 524,
        videoFile: GLA50,
        rusQuestion: "любовницы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a woman who is having a sexual relationship with a married man:",
        answer: "mistress",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 523,
        videoFile: GLA49,
        rusQuestion: "свиток",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a long roll of paper or similar material with usually official writing on it:",
        answer: "scroll",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 522,
        videoFile: GLA49,
        rusQuestion: "сумерки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the period just before it becomes completely dark in the evening:",
        answer: "twilight",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 521,
        videoFile: GLA48,
        rusQuestion: "чума",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a serious disease that kills many people, often used to refer to bubonic plague,",
        answer: "plague",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 520,
        videoFile: GLA47,
        rusQuestion: "квартал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an area of a town where a particular group of people live or work or where a particular activity happens:",
        answer: "quarter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 519,
        videoFile: GLA46,
        rusQuestion: "радоваться , ликует",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to feel or show great happiness about something:",
        answer: "rejoice",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 518,
        videoFile: GLA45,
        rusQuestion: "приветствую вас",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to give a greeting to someone, or to ask someone to do something:",
        answer: "bid you welcome",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 517,
        videoFile: GLA45,
        rusQuestion: "подданный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who lives in or who has the right to live in a particular country, especially a country with a king or queen:",
        answer: "subject",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 516,
        videoFile: GLA44,
        rusQuestion: "в конечном счете",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "finally, after a series of things have happened: used to emphasize the most important fact in a situation:",
        answer: "ultimately",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 515,
        videoFile: GLA43,
        rusQuestion: "переход",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a change from one form or type to another, or the process by which this happens:",
        answer: "transition",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 514,
        videoFile: GLA41,
        rusQuestion: "дезертир",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who leaves the armed forces without permission",
        answer: "deserter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 513,
        videoFile: GLA40,
        rusQuestion: "ремесло , профессия",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a job, especially one that needs special skill, that involves working with your hands:",
        answer: "trade",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 512,
        videoFile: GLA39,
        rusQuestion: "лезвие , клинок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the flat part on a knife or similar tool or weapon, with a very thin edge used for cutting:",
        answer: "blade",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 511,
        videoFile: GLA38,
        rusQuestion: "убитый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "past participle of slay",
        answer: "slain",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 510,
        videoFile: GLA37,
        rusQuestion: "благоразумный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "careful and avoiding risks:",
        answer: "prudent",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 509,
        videoFile: GLA36,
        rusQuestion: "хирург , военный врач",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a doctor who is specially trained to perform medical operations",
        answer: "surgeon",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 508,
        videoFile: GLA35,
        rusQuestion: "оплакивать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to express sadness and feeling sorry about something:",
        answer: "lament",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 507,
        videoFile: GLA34,
        rusQuestion: "зарезать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to kill or cut up an animal for meat:",
        answer: "butcher",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 506,
        videoFile: GLA33,
        rusQuestion: "провал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the fact of someone or something not succeeding:",
        answer: "failure",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 505,
        videoFile: GLA33,
        rusQuestion: "вина , ошибка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a mistake, especially something for which you are to blame:",
        answer: "fault",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 504,
        videoFile: GLA32,
        rusQuestion: "соответствовать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to be as good as something:",
        answer: "live up to",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 503,
        videoFile: GLA31,
        rusQuestion: "находчивость",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the ability to make decisions and act on your own:",
        answer: "resourcefulness",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 502,
        videoFile: GLA30,
        rusQuestion: "успеха , превосходить , ",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to be extremely good at something:",
        answer: "excel",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 501,
        videoFile: GLA29,
        rusQuestion: "умеренность , сдержанность",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "control of your own behaviour, such as not drinking or eating too much",
        answer: "temperance",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 500,
        videoFile: GLA28,
        rusQuestion: "сила духа",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "courage over a long period:",
        answer: "fortitude",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 499,
        videoFile: GLA27,
        rusQuestion: "добродетел",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a good moral quality in a person, or the general quality of being morally good:",
        answer: "virtue",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 498,
        videoFile: GLA26,
        rusQuestion: "долг",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "something that you have to do because it is part of your job, or something that you feel is the right thing to do:",
        answer: "duty",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },{
        id: 497,
        videoFile: GLA25,
        rusQuestion: "достоинство",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "calm, serious, and controlled behaviour that makes people respect you:",
        answer: "dignity",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 496,
        videoFile: GLA24,
        rusQuestion: "руководство",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "help and advice about how to do something or about how to deal with problems connected with your work, education, or personal relationships:",
        answer: "guidance",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 495,
        videoFile: GLA23,
        rusQuestion: "оплакивал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to feel or express great sadness, especially because of someone's death:",
        answer: "mourn",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 494,
        videoFile: GLA22,
        rusQuestion: "преемственность , право наследования",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a process in which someone automatically takes an official position or job after someone else:",
        answer: "succession",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 493,
        videoFile: GLA21,
        rusQuestion: "наживать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to get or obtain something: ",
        answer: "acquire",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 492,
        videoFile: GLA20,
        rusQuestion: "искалеченный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "unable to walk or move in the usual way because of injury or a medical condition",
        answer: "crippled",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 491,
        videoFile: GLA19,
        rusQuestion: "виноград",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small, round, purple or pale green fruit that you can eat or make into wine:",
        answer: "grape",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 490,
        videoFile: GLA18,
        rusQuestion: "почва , земля",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the material on the surface of the ground in which plants grow:",
        answer: "soil",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 489,
        videoFile: GLA17,
        rusQuestion: "инжир",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sweet, soft, purple or green fruit with many seeds, or a tree from the ficus family on which these grow",
        answer: "figs",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 488,
        videoFile: GLA16,
        rusQuestion: "тополь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a tall tree with branches that form a thin pointed shape:",
        answer: "poplar",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 487,
        videoFile: GLA15,
        rusQuestion: "травы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of plant whose leaves are used in cooking to give flavour to particular dishes or in making medicine:",
        answer: "herbs",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 486,
        videoFile: GLA14,
        rusQuestion: "расколотый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to separate or divide, or cause something to separate or divide, often violently:",
        answer: "cleave",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 485,
        videoFile: GLA13,
        rusQuestion: "пролитый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause to) flow, move, fall, or spread over the edge or outside the limits of something:",
        answer: "spilt",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 484,
        videoFile: GLA12,
        rusQuestion: "ссора , льстить , обманывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to argue over something that is not important: to praise someone in order to make them feel attractive or important, sometimes in a way that is not sincere: to persuade someone that something false is the truth, or to keep the truth hidden from someone for your own advantage: ",
        answer: "squabble flatter deceive",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 483,
        videoFile: GLA11,
        rusQuestion: "под влиянием",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to affect or change how someone or something develops, behaves, or thinks:",
        answer: "influenced by",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 482,
        videoFile: GLA10,
        rusQuestion: "медовый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used to describe speech or a person's voice when it is gentle and pleasant to listen to, sometimes in a way that is not sincere",
        answer: "honeyed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 481,
        videoFile: GLA9,
        rusQuestion: "остерегаться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used to warn someone to be very careful about something or someone:",
        answer: "beware of",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 480,
        videoFile: GLA8,
        rusQuestion: "казармы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a building or group of buildings where soldiers live:",
        answer: "barracks",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 479,
        videoFile: GLA7,
        rusQuestion: "триумф",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a very great success, achievement, or victory (= when you win a war, fight, or competition), or a feeling of great satisfaction or pleasure caused by this:",
        answer: "triumph",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 478,
        videoFile: GLA6,
        rusQuestion: "доблесть",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "great courage:",
        answer: "valor",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 477,
        videoFile: GLA5,
        rusQuestion: "величество",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the title used to speak to or about a king or queen:",
        answer: "majesty",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 476,
        videoFile: GLA4,
        rusQuestion: "непрерывный интриги",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "never stopping, especially in an annoying or unpleasant way: making clever, secret plans, often to deceive others:",
        answer: "incessant scheming",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 475,
        videoFile: GLA3,
        rusQuestion: "урожай",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(the total amount collected of) a plant such as a grain, fruit, or vegetable grown in large amounts:",
        answer: "crop",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 474,
        videoFile: GLA2,
        rusQuestion: "кавалерия",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the group of soldiers in an army who fight in tanks, or (especially in the past) on horses",
        answer: "cavalry",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 473,
        videoFile: GLA1,
        rusQuestion: "наклонять , худой",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(of a person) thin and in good physical condition:",
        answer: "lean",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
]